

Arya Vaziri

Date of birth: 17/07/1989

Nationality: Iranian

Gender: Male

CONTACT





arya.vaziri@gmail.com



(+98) 9121219255

www.aaryaa.ir

LinkedIn: https://

www.linkedin.com/in/arya-

vaziri-7116ab206/ Instagram: https://

www.instagram.com/aryavaziri/

Whatsapp Messenger: +9891212

19255

ABOUT ME

I'm an enthusiastic and entrepreneur minded industrial engineer and product designer who has designed, built, automated and installed numerous industrial machines. I've worked as a project manager and product designer who has many years of experience (+5 years) with various industrial mechanical machines and electronical equipment such as PLC in order to produce innovative products and solutions.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

09/2007 - 01/2014 - Isfahan, Iran

B.Eng textile engineering

Isfahan University of Technology

iut.ac.ir

01/2019 - 09/2019

Professional frontend development cert.

Tehran Institute of Technology

www.mftplus.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2019 - CURRENT - Tehran, Iran

Chief Product Designer and Board Member

Arooz industrial valve

This start-up is stablished to supply a wide range of industrial products and solutions.

- Designed, produced, and assembled pneumatic angled seat valves .
- 3D modeling using Solidworks.

11/2019 - 05/2021 - Tehran, Iran

Product Owner and Chief designer

Arya machinery

- Design energy-saving high-temperature fabric dyeing machines, including full automated system using pneumatic valves and PLC
- Responsible for designing UI/UX design and digital architecture of the
- Scrum master responsible for a team of 4 including TIG welders and
- Procurement Management.
- Organize out-sourced activities such as laser cut, casting and rolling.

01/2014 - 08/2018 - Tehran, Iran

Maintenance and repair engineer

Alvan naghsh pood

- Automate all product line machines, containing dyeing section and finishing section.
- Build first high-temperature fabric dyeing machine in Iran.
- Overhaul product line, fixing and repairing broken parts, as well as building new parts...
- Experience in sheet metal work such as 2D and 3D designing, cutting, grinding, rolling, bending, and different kinds of welding, including TIG welding process.
- · Assemble a 1988 Stork printing machine, fully repaired, revisioned, installed, and PLC-controlled automated.

03/2010 - 04/2021 - Safadasht, Iran

PLC programmer and developer

Mehrsan machinery

- programmed PLCs and helped to improve proficiency, including textile finishing machines such as dryer, balloon squeezer, tube fabric thermofix and compactor.
- Overhauled the factory and upgraded industrial modern systems.

06/2008 - 01/2014 - Tehran, Iran

Trainee

Alvan Naghsh Pood

- Learnt about textile machinery.
- Became familiar with automation systems.
- Operated various types of machines.
- Worked in chemical laboratory, for exampled color similarity with fabric dyes.
- Worked with tools and lathing machin.

2009 - 2010 - Isfahan, Iran

Trainee

Diba control

• Industrial electric equipment manual assembly.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Persian

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening	Reading	Spoken	Spoken	Writing
C1	C1	production	interaction	B2
		B2	B2	

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office / Microsoft Project / AutoCAD / Python / Raspberry Pi / PLC / HTML / CSS / Javascript / Jquery / CNC milling / Industrial Electricity / Autodesk AutoCAD (Optimal Knowledge) / Solidworks (Professional Proficiency) / ICS/SCADA

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

TIG welding

I've learnt how to weld stainless steel with TIG welding process practically until intermediate level.

Molding and CNC-machining

Camping

Singing

Travelling

Music

Skiing

Teamwork

Meditating

Safari driving

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Effective interpersonal skills

- Leadership.
- Teamwork.
- Responsibility.
- Flexibility.
- Crisis management.
- Motivation.
- Innovation.

PROJECTS

06/2021 - 11/2021

Timber autoclave

• Designed, assembled and automated a wood treatment machine.

07/2021 - 09/2021

Wax dosing machine

- Electricity and automation of a wax dosing machine.
- Helped with giving advices about the machine's hydraulic system during building procedure.

03/2020 - 05/2020

Tubular compactor

• PLC programming and automation of first Iran-made Tubular fabric compactor machine for Mehrsan machinery.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

2004

Student mathematics Olympiad

RECOMMENDATIONS

- Dr. Shahram Seyyed CEO at Alvan Naghsh Pood <u>shahramseyed@gmail.com</u> (+98) 9121838857
 - My manager at Alvan Naghsh Pood.
- Dr. Akbar Khoddami Associate professor <u>khoddami@cc.iut.ac.ir</u> (+98) 313 3915033
 - My professor at Department of Textile Engineering.
- Dr. Hossein Tavanaee Associate professor <u>tavanai@cc.iut.ac.ir</u> (+98) 31339 15030
 - My supervising professor at Isfahan University of Technology.
- Asghar Mehri CEO at Mehrsan machinery <u>mehrsan.machinery@gmail.com</u> (+98) 9122648721
 - My manager at Mehrsan machinery.